## RUDRA UPADHYAY, E.I.T., M.S.E.

Email: Upadhyay.rudra@gmail.com ||Mobile: +14809399269||8, Francis Lundy Street, Brampton, ON, Canada L6Y4Y4

#### **SUMMARY**

Detail oriented and highly motivated structural engineer and EIT certified with wide-ranging DSA and OSHPD experience varying from site-specific stick-built projects to pre-fabricated modular structures. Extensive designing and engineering experience in materials such as steel, timber, concrete, masonry and light gage steel. Holds firm grasp of ASCE, NDS, AISC, ACI, AISI, IS, CBC and IBC codes for lateral and gravity design. Passionate for creative design problem solving of wide-ranging complicated structural systems. Structural design calculations of various projects and professional references are available upon request.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Master of Science – Construction Engineering** 

Arizona State University, Tempe

08/2014 - 12/2015

**Bachelor of Science – Civil Engineering** 

Gujarat Technological University

06/2010-06/2014

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Coding Languages: C, C++, MATLAB, MATHCAD

Structural Design and Modelling Software: STAAD.Pro, SAP 2000, RISA-3D, CBEAM, ENERCALC, STRUCALC, ETABS

Drafting/Designing Software: AUTOCAD 2D/3D, AUTODESK REVIT, CIVIL 3D, MICROSTATION, BIM

Concepts: Construction Administration, Estimation, Scheduling, CPM, PERT, FEM

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Staff Structural Engineer**

Orion Structural Engineering, INC.

02/2016 - Current

San Diego, California

- Execution of extensive structural engineering analysis and detail drafting as necessary to complete the project within the timeline.
- Red-lining / marking building plans and details for drafter with appropriate guidance.
- Extensive DSA and OSHPD experience of 3.5 years.
- Extensive involvement in designing of 70 school projects of steel, wood shear wall and moment frame pre-fabricated modular constructions as well as pre-cast concrete tilt-up panels.
- > Conducted periodic local construction site visits for foundation reinforcement as well as structural frame inspection.
- ➤ Collaborated with various general contractors and communicated site-specific issues as well as responded to RFIs.
- > Designed retrofitting projects for residential, industrial and commercial projects ranging up to 20 million USD.
- > Reviewed architectural, construction documents and approval of shop drawings.

## Junior Project Engineer

08/2015-02/2016

STRUKTUR Studio, L.L.C.

Scottsdale, Arizona

Summer Intern

04/2015 - 07/2015

LAM Structural Engineering L.L.C.

Tempe, Arizona

# PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Excellent organizational, written and verbal communication skills.
- Creative ability to adapt to changing customer profiles and work under pressure in a real-time environment.
- Proficiency in basic structural engineering principles and practices.
- > Strong analytical knowledge and understanding of engineering principles.
- Excellent planning and time management skills to meet strict deadlines.
- > Strong working knowledge of Microsoft Suite and a range of software programs for design and modeling.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Seismic Analysis of Modhera Sun Temple, IJRET, ISSN 2319-1163
- Seismic Study of Modhera Heritage Site, Conference SEC-2014, IIT Delhi, 12/2014, ISBN:978-93-84898-72-4
- ➤ Seismic Analysis of Rani Ki Vav (Step Well), IJSRD, 07/2014 Volume-2 Issue 5, ISSN:2321-0613
- Numerical Study of Brick Panel in Plane Loading", NCEETM, ISBN 978-81-923049-9-1
- > Comparative Parametric Study of Brick Panel for Linear Static and Modal Analysis, IJRET, ISSN:2319-1163